Inventory of the Erich Knapp papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Die Grünen file, 1966-1985
  - Friedenspolitik correspondence and printed matter, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 18:3-5; 30:3-4; 51:1-53:4)
  - Saarbrücken Kongress correspondence and printed matter, 1980 (Box-folder 18:6-8)
  - Nordrhein Westfalen correspondence and printed matter, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 27:3-5; 53:5-54:1)
  - General printed matter, 1966-1985, undated (Box-folder 30:4-31:5; 67:7-68:1)
  - Posters, 1980-1981 (Map case)
- Writings, 1950-2005
  Consists of handwritten notes, drafts, and published copies of Knapp's research and articles on various topics primarily related to religion and history.
  - Articles in Newsletters, Magazines, and Journals, 1955-1959, 1975-1986, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 33:4-6; 35:6-8; 72:1-2; 109:2-6)
  - Notes, 1950-1994
    - Anti-nuclear movement, 1982 (Box-folder 48:1)
    - "Nazis in the Freie Demokratische Partei,", 1950-1962 (Box-folder 35:4-7)
    - General, 1959, undated (Box-folder 32:4; 59:4; 114:4)
    - Theology, 1984, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 34:6; 41:6; 62:5)
    - Prussian history, undated (Box-folder 91:2-5)
    - African religions, 1992, undated (Box-folder 104:1-2)
    - German history, 1975-1978, undated (Box-folder 114:5-115:4)
  - "Hass oder Spanischer Herbst," draft, undated (Box-folder 84:5-6)
  - "Skizzen zu einer bundesdeutschen Euroasienpolitik," drafts and related correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 91:14-92:2)
  - "Kerndeutschland," drafts, notes, 1966-1968, undated (Box-folder 92:6-93:6)
  - "Zur Urteilsschrift des Kriegsrichters Schwein," notes, 2002 (Box-folder 113:3)
- Preussischer Nationalkongress file, 1987-1999
  Consists of correspondence and printed matter related to the Preussischer Nationalkongress, an organization to promote political autonomy for the former Prussian state, of which Knapp was a member.
  - Correspondence, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 43:2-45:11; 101:7-8)
  - Printed matter, 1994-1995
    - "Die Macht der islamischen Order," essay and related correspondence, 1994 (Box-folder 46:1-2)
    - "Consitutional Declaration Concerning the Re-establishment of the Free State of Prussia,", 1995 (Box-folder 46:3)
  - Blank stationary, undated (Box-folder 46:4)
- Project Musa file, 1987-1996
  Consists of correspondence and printed matter related to Project Musa, a project initiated by Knapp to advocate for the South African Muslim community.
  - Correspondence, 1987-1996 (Box-folder 42:1-12)
  - Architectural plans, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 42:6; 121:5)
  - Photographs and negatives, undated (Box-folder 42:13)
- Reichsbanner Schwarz-Rot-Gold/Bund Aktiver Demokraten file, 1962-1979
  Consists of correspondence and printed matter related to the Reichsbanner Schwarz-Rot-Gold, a political organization that dissolved and reestablished itself as the Bund Aktiver Demokraten, and of which Knapp was a member.
  - "Auswärtige Korrespondenz,", 1970-1979 (Box-folder 81:6-7)
  - Baden-Würtemburg correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 80:4-6)
  - Bonn correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 81:4-5)
  - General Correspondence, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 76:1-79:5)
  - Hannover correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 79:6)
  - Hessen correspondence, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 81:2-3)
  - Leverkusen correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 80:7-81:1)
  - Printed Matter, 1970-1973
    - "Das Reichsbanner," newsletter, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 79:7-80:2)
  - Photographs, 1970 (Box-folder 80:3)
- Rheinland Independence file, 1976-1984
  Consists of correspondence and printed matter related to various organizations involved with a movement to promote political autonomy of the Rhein region of western Germany.
  - Correspondence, 1962, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 26:4)
  - Printed matter, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 86:6-87:6)
  - Notes, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 87:2-6)
- Sozialdemokratische Partei file, 1959-1978
  Consists of correspondence and printed matter related to the Sozialdemokratische Partei of which Knapp was a member.
  - "Grundsatzprogramm,", 1959 (Box-folder 56:9)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1978 (Box-folder 56:10-57:5)
- Education file, 1950-1968
  Consists of correspondence and printed matter related to Knapp's university career, in particular his attendence of Kansas University as a Fullbright scholar.
  - Notes and Essays, 1950-1968, undated (Box-folder 74:8-75:3)
  - School yearbook, 1952 (Box-folder 75:4)
  - University of Kansas File, 1954-1962
    - Correspondence, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 75:9)
    - Notes, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 75:7-8)
    - Student directories, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 75:5-6)
- Travel file, 1938-1990, undate
  Consists of travel guides, maps, and brochures related to Knapp's travels to countries, including Spain, France, Morocco, Switzerland, and Thailand.
  - Brochures and magazines, 1954-1990 (Box-folder 36:1-7; 82:4-83:5)
  - Maps, 1938-1942, undated (Box-folder 36:8; 82:2-4)
  - Travel itineraries, 1975 (Box-folder 83:6)
  - Travel receipts, 1979-1981, undated (Box-folder 83:7-84:1)
- Ephemera, 1981
  - Train tickets, 1981 (Box-folder 55:1)
- Nuclear disarmament posters, 1981 (Map case)